BENJAMIN T. BRIER

(484)844-4113

ben.brier14@gmail.com

203 Clwyd Road Bala Cynwyd, PA 19004

Profile

United States Army National Guardsman with a combined service of eight years within the military, a year as an independent contractor supporting DoD contracts that include SRP exercises and JSOC training, and served in Afghanistan as a private military contractor. My expertise range from strategizing and utilizing force protection assets to counter various threats, surveillance role-playing, training of USASOC teams in various environments, reconnaissance, gathering of intelligence, strong knowledge of administrative computer software, and an ability to lead and work with others to accomplish any task set forth by my superiors. I currently hold an active government Secret Clearance.

Experience

Marketing Manager, JDog; Glenside, PA - 2018- 2019

- Primarily focused on utilizing standard marketing and guerrilla marketing techniques and tactics to reach a larger percentage of the franchise's assigned population and to strengthen brand trust.
- Analyzed and interpreted local population data to determine the most effective marketing strategies and campaigns to reach target audience. Utilized social media software such as Instagram and Facebook to post daily photographs, videos, and promotional advertisements.
- In conjunction with improving social media presence, employed simple and
 effective guerrilla marketing techniques such as door-hangers, yard signs,
 business cards, decals, business to business relationships, and positioning of
 wrapped trucks and trailers to enforce brand trust and reach every demographic
 within the given population.

Operations Coordinator, JDog; Berwyn, PA — 2017- 2018

- Primarily tasked with acting as the liaison between the customers, franchisees, and the franchisor to ensure company goals and operational tasks were met on a day-to-day basis.
- Utilized software such as Microsoft Excel, Powerpoint, Microsoft Office, Skype, Slack, G Suite, and other similar software to collect, organize, and distribute information and data to the franchisees. This information was used to identify problems in the operations process in order to resolve them rapidly and create strategic plans for improvement.

 Tasked with improving and organizing Bootcamp, a program for new franchisees in which they learn to successfully operate their business on various levels, including financial planning and strategizing, marketing techniques, effective communication, sales techniques, and employee hiring.

Force Protection Officer, Triple Canopy; Afghanistan — 2016- 2017

- Performed internal guard services on a classified compound within Afghanistan.
- To maintain security, our team was tasked with manning vehicle and personnel Entry Control Points (ECP), towers along the perimeter of the compound, internal roving patrols, and armed escort guard services.
- At the multiple Entry Control Points we performed screener duties by searching visitors and their vehicles using hand-held metal detectors, mirrors to scan for any contraband or explosives underneath the vehicles, and a hands-on method of searching through the cabin and engine bay.
- In order to provide security from the towers, we were trained to utilize both lethal
 and non-lethal methods of defensive security counter measures to include but not
 limited to shotguns, paintball guns, and Common Remotely Operated Weapon
 Stations (CROWS).

Surveillance Role Player/OPFOR; Washington D.C. - 2015- 2016

- Act as a surveillance role-player to the Joint Counter Intelligence Training
 Academy in various locations in the Northern Virginia Area. In accordance with
 contract requirements, performed surveillance on student teams using proven
 methods of effective surveillance to gather intelligence and train the subject on
 counter-intelligence tactics, both on foot and in vehicles.
- Supported USASOC in training exercises. Acted as an adversarial force in a variety of different real-world scenarios to train the client in high-value target acquisition, effective CQB techniques, and efficient small squad tactics.

Pennsylvania Army National Guard; Philadelphia, PA - 2011- Current

- Currently assigned to A-Troop, 1/104th CAV, a light reconnaissance unit, serving as a team leader in my section and a HMMWV Gunner in my squad. I am tasked with leading two men and reporting to my squad leader.
- Duties as a crew member aboard the HMMWV include but are not limited to: knowledge of the mechanical and electronic aspects of the vehicle, ability to operate and maintain the various weapons platforms, as well as the M9 pistol, proficiency in the use of the FBCB2, radios, and other communication equipment, and understanding of light-armored platoon tactics.

Cavalry Scout proficient in small unit tactics, land navigation techniques, creating
observation posts using cover and concealment, observing hostile forces and
sending timely and accurate reports to the commander, calling for artillery fire via
radio communication, and engaging enemy forces or breaking contact dependent
on situational needs and standard operating procedures.

Education & Organizations

- Rosemont College— Bachelors of Science In Criminal Justice (Expected Graduation— Fall 2019)
- University of Pennsylvania LPS Coding Program (Expected Graduation January, 2020)
- The Haverford School High School Diploma
- Small Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (Raven) Course—Master Qualified, Honor Graduate
- Javelin Training Course
- Armored Reconnaissance Specialist Course
- First Troop Philadelphia City Cavalry—Corporal, Entertainment Chair
- Freemason, St. Alban Lodge 529—Third Degree Master Mason